<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110400</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oxidative stability of rice flour during storage under thermal oxidation and light irradiation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1359</StartPage><EndPage>1370</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1359-1370</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01790-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The oxidative stabilities of brown and white rice flours from two varieties, Baromi2 and Samkwang, were assessed under conditions of thermal oxidation at 60&#xa0;&#xb0;C and fluorescent light irradiation at 25&#xa0;&#xb0;C. Baromi2, designed for rice flour production, and Samkwang, intended for grain consumption, exhibited differing oxidative stabilities. Utilizing solid-phase microextraction-GC/MS and electronic nose techniques, the volatile profiles and the presence of singlet oxygen were investigated. Baromi2 displayed significantly lower oxidative stability than Samkwang under both thermal and light stress (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05), largely attributed to its higher lipid and riboflavin content. The presence of 1-octen-3-ol, a primary volatile associated with singlet oxygen, was notably detected in Baromi2 brown rice flour, whereas an increased number of aldehyde volatiles were identified in its white rice flour variant. A PCA executed through the electronic nose technique substantiated the distinction in volatile profiles between Baromi2 and Samkwang, as influenced by thermal and light irradiation treatments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2024. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>SeungHyun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Sungkyunkwan University, 2066 Seobu-ro, Jangan-gu, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do 440-746 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04q78tk20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.264381.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 989X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>JungMin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Sungkyunkwan University, 2066 Seobu-ro, Jangan-gu, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do 440-746 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04q78tk20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.264381.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 989X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwak</LastName><ForeName>Jieun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Crop Post-Harvest Technology Research Division, Rural Development of Administration, National Institute of Crop Science, Pyeongchang, Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/03xs9yg50</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.420186.9</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0636 2782</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oh</LastName><ForeName>WonYoung</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmacy Dongduk Women's University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/039p7ck60</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412059.b</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0532 5816</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>JaeHwan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0118-6233</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Sungkyunkwan University, 2066 Seobu-ro, Jangan-gu, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do 440-746 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04q78tk20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.264381.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 989X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food Flavor Sensory Research Center, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04q78tk20</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.264381.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 989X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Light irradiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rice flour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermal oxidation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01790-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chai D, Li C, Zhang X, Yang J, Liu L, Xu X, Du M, Wang Y, Chen Y, Dong L. Analysis of volatile compounds from wheat flour in the heating process. International Journal of Food Engineering. 15 (2019)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi OJ, Jung HN, Shim KH. Physicochemical properties of powdered, soft and hard type rice flour by different milling methods. Korean Journal of Food Preservation. 22:174-181 (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias RJ, Kellerby SS, Decker EA. Antioxidant activity of proteins and peptides. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition. 48:430-441 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18464032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng T, Zhuang H, Ye R, Jin Z, Xu X, Xie Z. Analysis of volatile compounds of Mesona Blumes gum/rice extrudates via GC&#x2013;MS and electronic nose. Sensors and Actuators B: Chemical. 160:964-973 (2011)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankel EN. Chemistry of autoxidation: mechanism, products and flavor significance. 1&#x2013;37. In: Flavor Chemistry of Fats and Oils. Min DB and Smouse TH. AOCS, Champaign. (1985)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerardi C, Durante M, Tufariello M, Grieco F, Giovinazzo G. Effects of time and temperature on stability of bioactive molecules, color and volatile compounds during storage of grape pomace flour. Applied Sciences. 12:3956 (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha SK, Kim BK, Hwang WH, Mo YJ, Jeong JM, Lee DK, Kim WJ, Kim JJ, Jeung JU. Early maturing rice variety &#x201c;Baromi2&#x201d; with a floury endosperm and suitable for dry-milling of rice grain. Korean Journal of Breeding Science. 54:433-441 (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MF, Rashid M, Sidhu R, Mullins R, Mayhew SL. A simplified, specific HPLC method of assaying thiamine and riboflavin in mushrooms. International Journal of Food Science (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6378034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30854396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Lu L, Guo Z, Zhu Z. Volatile compounds, affecting factors and evaluation methods for rice aroma: A review. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology. 97:136-146 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang SH, Lee JH, Park KJ. Profile change of the volatile and non&#x2010;volatile compounds in dried or baked laver by photooxidation.&#xa0;Journal of Food Science.&#xa0;89:998-1011 (2024)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38161275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaisut D, Prachayawarakorn S, Varanyanond W, Tungtrakul P, Soponronnarit S. Accelerated aging of jasmine brown rice by high-temperature fluidization technique. Food Research International. 42:674-681 (2009)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon J, Lee SH, Choi YM, Choung MG. Contents of water-soluble vitamins as thiamine, riboflavin, and niacin in husked and milled rice of Korean new bred cultivars. Journal of the Korean Society of Food Science and Nutrition. 49:961-968 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Zhang Q, Li Z, Yin C, Feng N, Shi Y. Determination of the quality of tea from different picking periods: An adaptive pooling attention mechanism coupled with an electronic nose. Postharvest Biology and Technology. 197:112214 (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katragadda HR, Fullana A, Sidhu S, Carbonell-Barrachina &#xc1;A. Emissions of volatile aldehydes from heated cooking oils. Food Chemistry. 120:59-65 (2010)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CH, Jo SB, Yoo KC, Kim MJ, Lee JH. Distribution of aldehydes and comparison of aldehydes with other oxidation parameters in oil matrices during autoxidation. Food Science and Biotechnology. 30:1195-1203 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8423876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim WS, Shin MS. The properties of rice flours prepared by dry-and wet-milling of soaked glutinous and normal grains. Korean Journal of Food Cookery Science. 23:908-918 (2007)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiralan M, Kayahan M, Kiralan SS, Ramadan MF. Effect of thermal and photo oxidation on the stability of cold-pressed plum and apricot kernel oils. European Food Research and Technology. 244:31-42 (2018)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo H, Kim S, Lee J. Comparison of physicochemical properties and oxidative stability of microencapsulated perilla oil powder prepared by freeze-drying and spray-drying. Food Science and Biotechnology. 32:1831-1839 (2023)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37781056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kum JS, Lee HY. The effect of the varieties and particle size on the properties of rice flour. Korean Journal of Food Science and Technology. 31:1542-1548 (1999)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampi AM, Damerau A, Li J, Moisio T, Partanen R, Forssell P, Piironen V. Changes in lipids and volatile compounds of oat flours and extrudates during processing and storage. Journal of Cereal Science. 62:102-109 (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Decker EA. Effects of metal chelators, sodium azide, and superoxide dismutase (SOD) on the oxidative stability in riboflavin photosensitized O/W emulsion systems. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 59:6271-6276 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21542578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Min DB. Changes of headspace volatiles in milk with riboflavin photosensitization. Journal of Food Science. 74:C563-C568 (2009)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19895461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Won YJ, Cho YC, Lee JH, Yang CI, Kim MK, Ahn EK, Suh JP, Lee SB, Jeon YH, Sung YK. &#x2018;Samkwang1&#x2019;, a medium maturing, multiple disease resistant, and high-quality rice. Korean Journal of Breeding Science. 50:490-496 (2018)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu L, Hu Z, Hu X, Li D, Tian S. Electronic tongue and electronic nose for food quality and safety. Food Research International. 162 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36461383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorrin JR. Key aroma compounds in oats and oat cereals. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 67:13778-13789 (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31017779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min DB, Boff JM. Chemistry and reaction of singlet oxygen in foods. Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety. 1:58-72 (2002)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33451241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molteberg EL, Magnus EM, BjOrge JM, Nilssoni A. Sensory and chemical studies of lipid oxidation in raw and heat-treated oat flours. Cereal Chemistry. 73:579-587 (1996)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SH, Oh WY, Lee JH. Evaluation of oxidative stability of rice oil from brown rice flour under thermal oxidation and light irradiation. Food Science and Biotechnology. 33:1839-1846 (2024)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11091002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38752120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh WY, Kim MJ, Lee JH. Approaches of lipid oxidation mechanisms in oil matrices using association colloids and analysis methods for the lipid oxidation. Food Science and Biotechnology. 32:1805-1819 (2023)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37781049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JW, Jang EY, Kim JY, Yi B, Kim MJ, Park KW, Lee JH. Effects of visible light irradiation on the oxidative stability in rice bran. Journal of Cereal Science. 58:178-181 (2013)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, Lee SK, Park HY, Choi HS, Cho DH, Lee KH, Han SI, Cho JH, Oh SK. Physicochemical properties of rice flour of different cultivars using wet and dry milling processes. Korean Journal of Crop Science 62:184-192 (2017)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan VA, Liao YC, Antille N, Sagalowicz L, Robert F, Godinot N. Delayed volatile compound release properties of self-assembly structures in emulsions. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 56:1072-1077 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18197619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin MS, Gang DO, Song JY. Effects of protein and transglutaminase on the preparation of gluten-free rice bread. Food Science and Biotechnology. 19:951-956 (2010)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Transparency Market Research. Rice Flour Market - Global Industry Analysis, Size, Share, Growth, Trends, and Forecast 2023&#x2013;2031. Available at: https://www.transparencymarketresearch.com/rice-flour-market.html. Accessed Sep. 04, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Wang R, Jing W, Zhang W. Quantitative dissection of lipid degradation in rice seeds during accelerated aging. Plant Growth Regulation. 66:49-58 (2012)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Lei B, Yang Z, Lei S. Self-repairing infrared electronic nose based on ensemble learning and PCA fault diagnosis. Infrared Physics and Technology. 127 (2022)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Guo H, Hou D, Laraib Y, Xue Y, Shen Q. Influence of temperature on storage characteristics of different rice varieties. Cereal Chemistry. 98:935-945 (2021)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>