<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110411</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Distillation method influences flavor characteristics of <i>Soju</i>.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1433</StartPage><EndPage>1436</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1433-1436</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01784-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The impact of the distillation method on the flavor characteristics of traditional <i>Soju</i> was investigated. Partial least squares-discrimination analysis (PLS-DA) was performed based on the volatile compounds detected by an electronic nose. This analysis revealed distinct flavor profiles when grouped by <i>Soju</i> samples, with ethyl acetate and isoamyl alcohol showing high variable importance in the projection (VIP) scores. When grouped by distillation method, ethyl acetate was identified as the critical compound distinguishing the flavor profiles of <i>Soju</i>. Compounds with fruity characteristics, such as ethyl acetate, isoamyl alcohol, and isoamyl acetate, were relatively more abundant in atmospheric distillation, while isobutanol, known for its alcoholic aroma, was more abundant in vacuum distillation. These findings may provide valuable insights into the impacts of the distillation process on the flavor characteristics of traditional <i>Soju</i>.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Jeong-Ah</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Biotechnology and Environmental Science, Kangwon National University, Chuncheon, 24341 Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01mh5ph17</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412010.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0707 9039</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Myoung-Dong</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3138-3481</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Kangwon National University, Chuncheon, 24341 Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01mh5ph17</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412010.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0707 9039</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Fermentation and Brewing, Kangwon National University, Chuncheon, 24341 Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01mh5ph17</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412010.6</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0707 9039</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Distillation method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electronic nose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethyl acetate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flavor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soju</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare no potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01784-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cha J, Chin YW, Lee JY, Kim TW, Jang HW. Analysis of volatile compounds in Soju, a Korean distilled spirit, by SPME-Arrow-GC/MS. Foods. 9: 1422 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7601619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HU, Kim TW, Lee SJ. Characterization of Korean distilled liquor, soju, using chemical, HS-SPME-GC-MS, and sensory descriptive analysis. Molecules. 27: 2429 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9028313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35458627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conner JM, Paterson A, Piggott JR. Release of distillate flavour compounds in Scotch malt whisky. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture. 79: 1015-1020 (1999)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr&#xe9;s M, Platikanov S, Tsakovski S, Tauler R. Comparison of the variable importance in projection (VIP) and the selectivity ratio (SR) methods for variable selection and interpretation. Journal of Chemometrics. 29: 528-536 (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JM, Kim TW, Lee SJ. Sensory and volatile profiles of Korean commercially distilled soju using descriptive analysis and HS-SPME-GC-MS. Foods. 9: 1330 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7555153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32967326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In HY, Lee TS, Lee DS, Noh BS. Quality characteristics of Soju mashes brewed by Korean traditional method. Korean Journal of Food Science and Technology. 27: 134-140 (1995)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang HR, Hwang HJ, Lee JE, Kim HR. Quantitative analysis of volatile flavor components in Korean alcoholic beverage and Japanese sake using SPME-GC/MS. Food Science and Biotechnology. 25: 979-985 (2016)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6049114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30263363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kov&#xe1;ts E. Gas-chromatographische charakterisierung organischer verbindungen. teil 1: retentionsindices aliphatischer halogenide, alkohole, aldehyde und ketone. Helvetica Chimica Acta. 41: 1915-1932 (1958)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DH, Lee YS, Cho CH, Park IT, Kim JH, Ahn BH. The qualities of liquor distilled from ipguk (koji) or nuruk under reduced or atmospheric pressure. Korean Journal of Food Science and Technology. 46: 25-32 (2014)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JW, Kang SA, Cheong C. Quality characteristics of distilled alcohols prepared with different fermenting agents. Journal of the Korean Society for Applied Biological Chemistry. 58: 275-283 (2015)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KYM, Paterson A, Piggott JR, Richardson GD. Origins of flavour in whiskies and a revised flavour wheel: a review. Journal of the Institute of Brewing. 107: 287-313 (2001)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YH, Eom TK, Cheong C, Cho HC, Kim IY, Lee YS, Kim MS, Yu SY, Jeong YH. Quality characteristics of spirits by different distillation and filtrations. Journal of the Korean Society of Food Science and Nutrition. 42: 2012-2018 (2013)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu Y, Yao Z, Xiao Z, Zhu G, Zhu J, Chen J. Sensory evaluation of the synergism among ester odorants in light aroma-type liquor by odor threshold, aroma intensity and flash GC electronic nose. Food Research International. 113: 102-114 (2018)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30195503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang Z, Chong J, Zhou G, de Lima Morais DA, Chang L, Barrette M, Gauthier C, Jacques P&#xc9;, Li S, Xia J. MetaboAnalyst 5.0: narrowing the gap between raw spectra and functional insights. Nucleic Acids Research. 49: 388-396 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poisson L, Schieberle P. Characterization of the key aroma compounds in an American bourbon whisky by quantitative measurements, aroma recombination, and omission studies. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 56: 5820-5826 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18582086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song CS, Ju HM, Kim JM. Effects of isoamyl acetate production in Makgeolli according to fermentation conditions. Journal of Life Science. 30: 162-168 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak HJ, Lee NR, Yang S, Kim SY, Lee CH. Qualitative and quantitative metabolite comparison of Korean traditional alcoholic beverages: Takju, Yakju, and Traditional-Soju. Foods. 13: 956 (2024)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10970447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38540946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon JA, Kwun SY, Cho SW, Park EH, Seo YH, Kim MD. Analysis of flavor characteristics of commercial makgeolli. Microbiology and Biotechnology Letters. 52: 37-43 (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenkevich IG. Kov&#xe1;ts retention index system. Encyclopedia of Chromatography. 3: 1304-1310 (2010)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>