<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of volatile and odor-active compounds in charcoal-grilled marinated beef using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry and gas chromatography-olfactometry.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1339</StartPage><EndPage>1349</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1339-1349</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01783-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Charcoal-grilled marinated beef (CMB) is a popular Korean food that has garnered worldwide attention. In this study, volatile and odor-active compounds generated in CMB were analyzed using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) and gas chromatography-olfactometry (GC-O). Solvent-assisted flavor extraction and solid-phase micro extraction were employed to extract the volatile compounds before GC-MS and GC-O analyses. In total, 196 compounds were identified in CMB. Certain heterocyclic compounds, such as pyrazines and thiazoles, could be produced by grilling at high temperatures. The formation of benzene derivatives and phenols could be attributed to charcoal grilling and marinade used. In the GC-O results, 3-methylsulfanylpropanal, 2-methoxyphenol, 1,3-benzothiazole, furaneol, 3-methylphenol, prop-2-ene-1-thiol, 2-ethyl-3,5-dimethylpyrazine, and 2,5-dimethylpyrazine exhibited relatively high flavor dilution factors. Based on these findings, sulfur-containing compounds, pyrazines, phenols, and aldehydes primarily influence the characteristic flavor of CMB.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Minjoo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, 03760 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/053fp5c05</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.255649.9</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2171 7754</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Young-Suk</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1343-5647</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, 03760 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/053fp5c05</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.255649.9</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2171 7754</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Charcoal-grilled marinated beef</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GC-MS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GC-O</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Odor-active compounds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Volatile compounds</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestNone of the authors of this study have any financial interests or conflicts of interest with industries or other parties.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01783-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe K, Myoda T, Nojima S. Identification and characterization of sulfur heterocyclic compounds that contribute to the acidic odor of aged garlic extract. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 69: 1020-1026 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahamed Z, Seo JK, Eom JU, Yang HS. Optimization of volatile compound extraction on cooked meat using HS-SPME-GC-MS, and evaluation of diagnosis to meat species using volatile compound by multivariate data analysis. LWT-Food Science and Technology. 188: 115374 (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi J, Li B, Chen Z, Yang Z, Ping C, Gao Y, Zhang Y, Zhang L. Comparative study of volatile flavor compounds in green onion (Allium fistulosum L.) processed with different cooking methods. International Journal of Gastronomy and Food Science. 35: 100878 (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blank I, Fay LB. Formation of 4-hydroxy-2, 5-dimethyl-3 (2 H)-furanone and 4-hydroxy-2 (or 5)-ethyl-5 (or 2)-methyl-3 (2 H)-furanone through Maillard reaction based on pentose sugars. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 44: 531-536 (1996)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleicher J, Ebner EE, Bak KH. Formation and analysis of volatile and odor compounds in meat&#x2014;a review. Molecules. 27(19): 6703 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9572956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho IH, Kim TH, Cho SK, Lee HJ, Kim YS. Analysis of volatile compounds in bulgogi. Food Science and Biotechnology. 11: 303-309 (2002)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delahunty CM, Eyres G, Dufour JP. Gas chromatography-olfactometry. Journal of Separation Science. 29(14): 2107-2125 (2006)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17069240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du W, Zhao M, Zhen D, Tan J, Wang T, Xie J. Key aroma compounds in Chinese fried food of youtiao. Flavour and Fragrance Journal. 35(1): 88-98 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escudero A, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Orte P, Cacho J, Ferreira V. Clues about the role of methional as character impact odorant of some oxidized wines. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 48: 4268-4272 (2000)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10995348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Est&#xe9;vez M, Morcuende D, Ventanas S, Cava R. Analysis of volatiles in meat from Iberian pigs and lean pigs after refrigeration and cooking by using SPME-GC-MS. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 51(11): 3429-3435 (2003)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12744679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SP, Kim YH, Lee NH, Heo YU. The physicochemical characteristics of marinated beef galbi under different cooking conditions. Journal of the Korean Society of Food Culture. 28(1): 78-88 (2013)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jele&#x144; HH, Gracka A. Analysis of black pepper volatiles by solid phase microextraction-gas chromatography: A comparison of terpenes profiles with hydrodistillation. Journal of Chromatography A. 1418: 200-209 (2015)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26427328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang IH. Taste of Korea. Daehan Textbook Co., Seoul, Korea. pp.160 (1987)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim CJ, Jung JY, Lee ES, Song HH. Research on improving the quality and storage of traditional seasoned ribs according to packaging method. Korean Society of Food Science and Technology. 34: 792-798 (2002)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TH, Lee SM, Kim YS, Kim KH, Oh S, Lee HJ. Aroma dilution method using GC injector split ratio for volatile compounds extracted by headspace solid phase microextraction. Food Chemistry. 83(1): 151-158 (2003)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosowska M, Majcher MA, Fortuna T. Volatile compounds in meat and meat products. Food Science and Technology. 37: 1-7 (2017)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosowska M, Majcher MA, Jele&#x144; HH, Fortuna T. Key aroma compounds in smoked cooked loin. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 66(14): 3683-3690 (2018)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29575895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SM, Kim SB, Kim YS. Determination of key volatile compounds related to long-term fermentation of soy sauce. Jounral of Food Science. 84(10): 2758-2776 (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31509249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Fan C, He W, Deng J, Yin H. Sulfur-containing amino acid methionine as the precursor of volatile organic sulfur compounds in algea-induced black bloom. Journal of Environmental Sciences. 25(1): 33-43 (2013)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23586297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng Q, Yan J, Wu R, Liu H, Sun Y, Wu N, Xiang J, Zheng L, Zhang J, Han B. Sustainable production of benzene from lignin. Nature Communications. 12(1): 4534 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8313573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34312395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mili&#x107; BL, Pileti&#x107; MV. The mechanism of pyrrole, pyrazine and pyridine formation in non-enzymic browning reaction. Food Chemistry. 13: 165-180 (1984)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mottram DS. Flavour formation in meat and meat products: a review. Food Chemistry. 62: 415-424 (1998)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nocentini C, Certini G, Knicker H, Francioso O, Rumpel C. Nature and reactivity of charcoal produced and added to soil during wildfire are particle-size dependent. Organic Geochemistry. 41: 682-689 (2010)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter TM, Eyres GT, Silcock P, Bremer PJ. Comparison of four extraction methods for analysis of volatile hop-derived aroma compounds in beer. Journal of Separation Science. 40: 4366-4376 (2017)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28887851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruther J, Baltes W. Sulfur-containing furans in commercial meat flavorings. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 42(10): 2254-2259 (1994)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibamoto T. Heterocyclic compounds found in cooked meats. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 28: 237-243 (1980)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6993523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimoda M, Shiratsuchi H, Nakada Y, Wu Y, Osajima Y. Identification and sensory characterization of volatile flavor compounds in sesame seed oil. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 44(12): 3909-3912 (1996)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail A, Al-Dalali S, Wang J, Xie J, Shakoor A, Asimi S, Shah H, Patil P. Aroma compounds identified in cooked meat: A review. Food Research International. 157: 111385 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35761641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suleman R, Hui T, Wang Z, Liu H, Zhang D. Comparative analysis of charcoal grilling, infrared grilling and superheated steam roasting on the colour, textural quality and heterocyclic aromatic amines of lamb patties. International Journal of Food science &amp; Technology. 55: 1057-1068 (2020)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specht K, Baltes W. Identification of volatile flavor compounds with high aroma values from shallow-fried beef. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry. 42(10): 2246-2253 (1994)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun A, Wu W, Soladoye OP, Aluko RE, Bak KH, Fu Y, Zhang Y. Maillard reaction of food-derived peptides as a potential route to generate meat flavor compounds: A review. Food Research International. 151: 110823 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34980374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Zhang W, Li H, Mao J, Guo C, Ding R, Wang Y, Fang L, Chen Z, Yang G. Analysis of volatile compounds in pears by HS-SPME-GC&#xd7; GC-TOFMS. Molecules. 24:795 (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6539139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Yang P, Liu J, Yang W, Qiang Y, Jia W, Han&#xa0;D, Zhang&#xa0;C,&#xa0;Purcaro&#xa0;G, Fauconnier ML. Study of the flavor dissipation mechanism of soy-sauce-marinated beef using flavor matrices. Food Chemistry. 437(Pt 1): 137890 (2024)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37926031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo KS, Pike LM. Determination of flavor precursor compound S-alk(en)yl-l-cysteine sulfoxides by an HPLC method and their distribution in Allium species. Scientia Horticulturae. 75(1-2): 1-10 (1998)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Wang T, Xie J, Xiao Q, Du W, Wang Y, Cheng J, Wang S. Meat flavor generation from different composition patterns of initial Maillard stage intermediates formed in heated cysteine-xylose-glycine reaction systems. Food Chemistry. 274: 79-88 (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>