<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40110627</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-3599</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of genetic counseling</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Genet Couns</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Understanding and issues related to next-generation sequencing among educated laypersons in India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2008</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2008</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jgc4.2008</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) is being widely used for preconception carrier screening of couples, newborn screening, and personalized and preventive treatments, although its knowledge is still limited in laypersons. In this study, we have assessed the understanding, attitudes, and concerns related to NGS in 103 educated laypersons in India. The study participants were contacted by a combination of methods, including offline and online platforms. An information sheet was provided to them detailing the basics of DNA and the use of NGS in identifying genetic disorders with the possible types of results. Those participants who answered all the questions were included in the study. The participants in this study demonstrated a good general understanding of the information sheet (80.3% average correct response). We also observed that the majority wished to know the results of secondary findings related to actionable and unactionable conditions. Most of them wanted to sequence all their genes in their body, given a chance, and they had a general willingness to share the results with their relatives. The majority also felt that they would be better prepared mentally if they had a genetic diagnosis and would take necessary health measures as directed by their physician. About half of them felt that knowing the result may cause them distress. About half of them also wished to undergo prenatal testing based on an uncertain result, which stresses the need for better education about the limitations of NGS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 National Society of Genetic Counselors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shambhavi</LastName><ForeName>Arya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Genetics, Sanjay Gandhi Postgraduate Institute of Medical Sciences, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moirangthem</LastName><ForeName>Amita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0756-9868</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Genetics, Sanjay Gandhi Postgraduate Institute of Medical Sciences, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Prabhaker</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4769-9106</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Informatics, Sanjay Gandhi Postgraduate Institute of Medical Sciences, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phadke</LastName><ForeName>Shubha R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6624-082X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Genetics, Sanjay Gandhi Postgraduate Institute of Medical Sciences, Lucknow, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BT/PR26428/MED/12/783/2017</GrantID><Agency>Department of Biotechnology, Ministry of Science and Technology, India</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Genet Couns</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9206865</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1059-7700</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059014" MajorTopicYN="Y">High-Throughput Nucleotide Sequencing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005820" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Testing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">India</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">attitudes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laypersons</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">next generation sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychosocial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">underrepresented populations</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jgc4.2008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, B., Christensen, K. D., Genetti, C. A., Parad, R. B., Robinson, J. O., Blout Zawatsky, C. L., Zettler, B., Beggs, A. H., Holm, I. A., Green, R. C., McGuire, A. L., Smith, H. S., Pereira, S., &amp; The BabySeq Project Team. (2022). Parental attitudes toward standard newborn screening and newborn genomic sequencing: Findings from the BabySeq study. Frontiers in Genetics, 13, 867371. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2022.867371</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtiani, S., Makela, N., Carrion, P., &amp; Austin, J. (2014). Parents' experiences of receiving their child's genetic diagnosis: A qualitative study to inform clinical genetics practice. American Journal of Medical Genetics Part A, 164(6), 1496&#x2013;1502. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.36525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballard, L. M., Horton, R. H., Fenwick, A., &amp; Lucassen, A. M. (2020). Genome sequencing in healthcare: Understanding the UK general public's views and implications for clinical practice. European Journal of Human Genetics, 28(2), 155&#x2013;164. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41431&#x2010;019&#x2010;0504&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bindhani, B. K., Devi, N. K., &amp; Nayak, J. K. (2020). Knowledge, awareness, and attitude of premarital screening with special focus on sickle cell disease: A study from Odisha. Journal of Community Genetics, 11(4), 445&#x2013;449. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12687&#x2010;020&#x2010;00471&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xed;r&#xf3;, K., Dombr&#xe1;di, V., Fekete, Z., B&#xe1;nyai, G., Boruzs, K., Nagy, A., &amp; &#xc1;d&#xe1;ny, R. (2020). Investigating the knowledge of and public attitudes towards genetic testing within the Visegrad countries: A cross&#x2010;sectional study. BMC Public Health, 20(1), 1380. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889&#x2010;020&#x2010;09473&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombard, Y., Abelson, J., Simeonov, D., &amp; Gauvin, F.&#x2010;P. (2013). Citizens' perspectives on personalized medicine: A qualitative public deliberation study. European Journal of Human Genetics, 21(11), 1197&#x2013;1201. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2012.300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowman&#x2010;Smart, H., Vears, D. F., Brett, G. R., Martyn, M., Stark, Z., &amp; Gyngell, C. (2022). &#x2018;Diagnostic shock&#x2019;: The impact of results from ultrarapid genomic sequencing of critically unwell children on aspects of family functioning. European Journal of Human Genetics, 30(9), 1036&#x2013;1043. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41431&#x2010;022&#x2010;01140&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clift, K., Macklin, S., Halverson, C., McCormick, J. B., Abu Dabrh, A. M., &amp; Hines, S. (2020). Patients' views on variants of uncertain significance across indications. Journal of Community Genetics, 11(2), 139&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12687&#x2010;019&#x2010;00434&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganne, P., Damagatla, M., &amp; Naidu, N. (2021). Knowledge of genetic eye diseases and genetic services and attitudes toward genetic testing and gene therapy. Taiwan Journal of Ophthalmology, 11(4), 372&#x2013;379. https://doi.org/10.4103/tjo.tjo_34_21</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girisha, K. M., Pande, S., Dalal, A., &amp; Phadke, S. R. (2020). Untapped opportunities for rare disease gene discovery in India. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 182(12), 3056&#x2013;3059. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.61866</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart, M. R., Biesecker, B. B., Blout, C. L., Christensen, K. D., Amendola, L. M., Bergstrom, K. L., Biswas, S., Bowling, K. M., Brothers, K. B., Conlin, L. K., Cooper, G. M., Dulik, M. C., East, K. M., Everett, J. N., Finnila, C. R., Ghazani, A. A., Gilmore, M. J., Goddard, K. A. B., Jarvik, G. P., &#x2026; Hindorff, L. A. (2019). Secondary findings from clinical genomic sequencing: Prevalence, patient perspectives, family history assessment, and health&#x2010;care costs from a multisite study. Genetics in Medicine, 21(5), 1100&#x2013;1110. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41436&#x2010;018&#x2010;0308&#x2010;x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaton, T. J., &amp; Chico, V. (2016). Attitudes towards the sharing of genetic information with at&#x2010;risk relatives: Results of a quantitative survey. Human Genetics, 135(1), 109&#x2013;120. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00439&#x2010;015&#x2010;1612&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneman, L., Timmermans, D. R. M., &amp; Wal, G. V. D. (2006). Public attitudes toward genetic testing: Perceived benefits and objections. Genetic Testing, 10(2), 139&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1089/gte.2006.10.139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurle, B., Citrin, T., Jenkins, J. F., Kaphingst, K. A., Lamb, N., Roseman, J. E., &amp; Bonham, V. L. (2013). What does it mean to be genomically literate?: National Human Genome Research Institute meeting report. Genetics in Medicine, 15(8), 658&#x2013;663. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2013.14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaphingst, K. A., Ivanovich, J., Biesecker, B. B., Dresser, R., Seo, J., Dressler, L. G., Goodfellow, P. J., &amp; Goodman, M. S. (2016). Preferences for return of incidental findings from genome sequencing among women diagnosed with breast cancer at a young age. Clinical Genetics, 89(3), 378&#x2013;384. https://doi.org/10.1111/cge.12597</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, P., Do Rosario, M. C., Hebbar, M., Sharma, S., Kausthubham, N., Nair, K. A. S., Bhat, Y. R., Lewis, L. E. S., Nampoothiri, S., Patil, S. J., Suresh, N., Bijarnia Mahay, S., Dua Puri, R., Pai, S., Kaur, A., Kc, R., Kamath, N., Bajaj, S., &#x2026; Shukla, A. (2021). Clinical and genetic spectrum of 104 Indian families with central nervous system white matter abnormalities. Clinical Genetics, 100(5), 542&#x2013;550. https://doi.org/10.1111/cge.14037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch, F., Best, S., Gaff, C., Downie, L., Archibald, A. D., Gyngell, C., Goranitis, I., Peters, R., Savulescu, J., Lunke, S., Stark, Z., &amp; Vears, D. F. (2024). Australian public perspectives on genomic newborn screening: Risks, benefits, and preferences for implementation. International Journal of Neonatal Screening, 10(1), 6. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijns10010006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manickam, K., McClain, M. R., Demmer, L. A., Biswas, S., Kearney, H. M., Malinowski, J., Massingham, L. J., Miller, D., Yu, T. W., &amp; Hisama, F. M. (2021). Exome and genome sequencing for pediatric patients with congenital anomalies or intellectual disability: An evidence&#x2010;based clinical guideline of the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics (ACMG). Genetics in Medicine, 23(11), 2029&#x2013;2037. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41436&#x2010;021&#x2010;01242&#x2010;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masih, S., Moirangthem, A., Shambhavi, A., Rai, A., Mandal, K., Saxena, D., Nilay, M., Agrawal, N., Srivastava, S., Sait, H., &amp; Phadke, S. R. (2022). Deciphering the molecular landscape of microcephaly in 87 Indian families by exome sequencing. European Journal of Medical Genetics, 65(6), 104520. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejmg.2022.104520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor, K., Jukes, T., Goobie, S., DiRaimo, J., Moran, G., Potter, B. K., Chakraborty, P., Rupar, C. A., Gannavarapu, S., &amp; Prasad, C. (2018). Psychosocial impact on mothers receiving expanded newborn screening results. European Journal of Human Genetics, 26(4), 477&#x2013;484. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41431&#x2010;017&#x2010;0069&#x2010;z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>on behalf of the DDD study, Middleton, A., Morley, K. I., Bragin, E., Firth, H. V., Hurles, M. E., Wright, C. F., &amp; Parker, M. (2016). Attitudes of nearly 7000 health professionals, genomic researchers and publics toward the return of incidental results from sequencing research. European Journal of Human Genetics, 24(1), 21&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2015.58</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pranav Chand, R., Vinit, W., Vaidya, V., Iyer, A. S., Shelke, M., Aggarwal, S., Magar, S., Danda, S., Moirangthem, A., Phadke, S. R., Goyal, M., Ranganath, P., Mistri, M., Shah, P., Shah, N., &amp; Kotecha, U. H. (2023). Proband only exome sequencing in 403 Indian children with neurodevelopmental disorders: Diagnostic yield, utility and challenges in a resource&#x2010;limited setting. European Journal of Medical Genetics, 66(5), 104730. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejmg.2023.104730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, K., Bijarnia&#x2010;Mahay, S., Ramprasad, V. L., Puri, R. D., Nair, S., Sharda, S., Saxena, R., Kohli, S., Kulshreshtha, S., Ganguli, I., Gujral, K., &amp; Verma, I. C. (2020). NGS&#x2010;based expanded carrier screening for genetic disorders in north Indian population reveals unexpected results &#x2013; A pilot study. BMC Medical Genetics, 21(1), 216. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12881&#x2010;020&#x2010;01153&#x2010;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson, A. N., Skinner, D., Perry, D. L., Scollon, S. R., Roche, M. I., &amp; Bernhardt, B. A. (2016). &#x201c;Not tied up neatly with a Bow&#x201d;: Professionals' challenging cases in informed consent for genomic sequencing. Journal of Genetic Counseling, 25(1), 62&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10897&#x2010;015&#x2010;9842&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma, I. C. (2000). Burden of genetic disorders in India. The Indian Journal of Pediatrics, 67(12), 893&#x2013;898. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02723953</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vermeulen, E., Henneman, L., van El, C. G., &amp; Cornel, M. C. (2014). Public attitudes towards preventive genomics and personal interest in genetic testing to prevent disease: A survey study. The European Journal of Public Health, 24(5), 768&#x2013;775. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckt143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waisbren, S. E. (2003). Effect of expanded newborn screening for biochemical genetic disorders on child outcomes and parental stress. JAMA, 290(19), 2564&#x2013;2572. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.290.19.2564</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilde, A., Meiser, B., Mitchell, P. B., &amp; Schofield, P. R. (2010). Public interest in predictive genetic testing, including direct&#x2010;to&#x2010;consumer testing, for susceptibility to major depression: Preliminary findings. European Journal of Human Genetics, 18(1), 47&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2009.138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn, J., Milo Rasouly, H., Vasquez&#x2010;Loarte, T., Saami, A. M., Weiss, R., Ziniel, S. I., Appelbaum, P. S., Wright Clayton, E., Christensen, K. D., Fasel, D., Green, R. C., Hain, H. S., Harr, M., Hoell, C., Kullo, I. J., Leppig, K. A., Myers, M. F., Pacyna, J. E., Perez, E. F., &#x2026; Holm, I. A. (2022). Do research participants share genomic screening results with family members? Journal of Genetic Counseling, 31(2), 447&#x2013;458. https://doi.org/10.1002/jgc4.1511</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>