<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110642</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0010</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the science of food and agriculture</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Food Agric</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of sequential inoculation on physicochemical properties, microbial community, and flavor metabolites of pineapple wine by non-Saccharomyces yeast and lactic acid bacteria.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jsfa.14207</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pineapple (Ananas comosus) is a popular subtropical fruit, but its acidic taste reduces the overall acceptability of fermented pineapple wine. In this study, juice from 'Cayenne' pineapple was inoculated with Hanseniaspora uvarum and Saccharomyces cerevisiae for alcoholic fermentation, followed by malolactic fermentation (MLF) with lactic acid bacteria (LAB). Physicochemical properties, microbial community, and flavor metabolites of the products were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Pineapple wine with an alcohol concentration ranging from 12% to 13% (v/v) showed significant increases in the levels of ethyl octanoate, ethyl acetate, and hexyl acetate. Sweetness and pleasant aroma of the final product were imparted by significant increases of approximately 1.26&#x2009;g&#x2009;L<sup>-1</sup> and 60.14&#x2009;mg&#x2009;L<sup>-1</sup> in glycerol and total ester concentrations, respectively, following sequential fermentation by H. uvarum and S. cerevisiae compared to S. cerevisiae alone. Among three LAB selected for MLF, Lactobacillus plantarum NTUAFM-B016 was the most compatible with H. uvarum and S. cerevisiae and displayed faster MLF completion (6-8&#x2009;days).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results provide a reference to increase consumer preference for pineapple wine and promote the application of non-Saccharomyces yeast-LAB co-culture in wine making. &#xa9; 2025 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Ting-Yu</ForeName><Initials>TY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Food Science Technology, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Chien-Hao</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food and Beverage Management, National Kaohsiung University of Hospitality and Tourism, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Yen-Tso</ForeName><Initials>YT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food and Nutrition, Providence University, Taichung City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Chen-Che</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Food Science Technology, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Seafood Science, National Kaohsiung University of Science and Technology, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Chang-Wei</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0533-9762</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, National Chung Hsing University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science, National Ilan University, Yilan City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Kuan-Chen</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0387-7804</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Food Science Technology, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biotechnology, National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Optometry, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, China Medical University Hospital, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science, Fu Jen Catholic University, New Taipei City, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Sci Food Agric</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376334</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-5142</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hanseniaspora uvarum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">co&#x2010;culture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lactic acid bacteria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malolactic fermentation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non&#x2010;Saccharomyces</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pineapple</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.14207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Lencastre Novaes LC, Jozala AF, Lopes AM, de Carvalho Santos&#x2010;Ebinuma V, Mazzola PG and Pessoa Junior A, Stability, purification, and applications of bromelain: a review. Biotechnol Prog 32:5&#x2013;13 (2016). https://doi.org/10.1002/btpr.2190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MF, Akhtar S and Anwar M, Nutritional value and medicinal benefits of pineapple. Int J Food Sci Nutr 1:84&#x2013;88 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebeler SE, Herszage J and Polaskova P, Wine flavor: chemistry in a glass. Chem Soc Rev 37:2478&#x2013;2489 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belda I, Ruiz J, Esteban&#x2010;Fern&#xe1;ndez A, Navascu&#xe9;s E, Marquina D, Santos A et al., Microbial contribution to wine aroma and its intended use for wine quality improvement. Molecules 22:189 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin N, Buykx P, Shevills C, Sullivan C, Clark L and Newbury&#x2010;Birch D, Population level effects of a mass media alcohol and breast cancer campaign: a cross&#x2010;sectional pre&#x2010;intervention and post&#x2010;intervention evaluation. Alcohol Alcohol 53:31&#x2013;38 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed ME, Ben&#x2010;Ezra V, Biggerstaff KD and Nichols DL, The effects of two bouts of high&#x2010;and low&#x2010;volume resistance exercise on glucose tolerance in normoglycemic women. J Strength Cond Res 26:251&#x2013;260 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano P, Fiore C, Paraggio M, Caruso M and Capece A, Function of yeast species and strains in wine flavour. Int J Food Microbiol 86:169&#x2013;180 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai YT, Hsieh CW, Lo YC, Liou BK, Lin HW, Hou CY et al., Isolation and identification of aroma&#x2010;producing non&#x2010;saccharomyces yeast strains and the enological characteristic comparison in wine making. LWT 154:112653 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira N, Pina C, Mendes F, Couto J, Hogg T and Vasconcelos I, Volatile compounds contribution of Hanseniaspora guilliermondii and Hanseniaspora uvarum during red wine vinifications. Food Control 22:662&#x2013;667 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Zhang Y, Qiu Y, Guo H, Ju H, Wang Y et al., Chemical composition, sensorial properties, and aroma&#x2010;active compounds of ciders fermented with Hanseniaspora osmophila and Torulaspora quercuum in co&#x2010;and sequential fermentations. Food Chem 306:125623 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou X, Sun L, Li Z, Deng X, Guan H, Luo C et al., An evaluation of yeast culture supplementation in the diet of pseudobagrus ussuriensis: growth,antioxidant activity, nonspecific immunity, and disease resistance to aeromonas hydrophila. Aquac Nutr (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hounhouigan MH, Linnemann AR, Soumanou MM and Van Boekel MA, Effect of processing on the quality of pineapple juice. Food Rev Int 30:112&#x2013;133 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanprasartsuk OO, Prakitchaiwattana C, Sanguandeekul R and Fleet GH, Autochthonous yeasts associated with mature pineapple fruits, freshly crushed juice and their ferments; and the chemical changes during natural fermentation. Bioresour Technol 101:7500&#x2013;7509 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou CY, Huang PH, Lai YT, Lin SP, Liou BK, Lin HW et al., Screening and identification of yeasts from fruits and their coculture for cider production. Ferment 8:1 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loira I, Morata A, Palomero F, Gonz&#xe1;lez C and Su&#xe1;rez&#x2010;Lepe JA, Schizosaccharomyces pombe: a promising biotechnology for modulating wine composition. Ferment 4:70 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benito S, Palomero F, Morata A, Calderon F, Palmero D and Su&#xe1;rez&#x2010;Lepe J, Physiological features of Schizosaccharomyces pombe of interest in making of white wines. Eur Food Res Technol 236:29&#x2013;36 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikhanj P and Kocher GS, Optimization of malolactic fermentation parameters with isolated and characterized lactic acid bacteria associated with grape berries. J Food Process 44:14905 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Capone DL, Roland A and Jeffery DW, Impact of accentuated cut edges, yeast strain, and malolactic fermentation on chemical and sensory profiles of Sauvignon blanc wine. Food Chem 400:134051 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2022.134051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Guo Z, Zhang W, Tan Q, Zhang L, Ge X et al., Quantitative relationship between cadmium uptake and the kinetics of phytochelatin induction by cadmium in a marine diatom. Sci Rep 6:35935 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunniff P and Association of Official Analytical Chemists, Official Methods of Analysis of AOAC International. Association of Official Analytical Chemists, Washington, DC (1995).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milanovic V, Ciani M, Oro L and Comitini F, Starmerella bombicola influences the metabolism of Saccharomyces cerevisiae at pyruvate decarboxylase and alcohol dehydrogenase level during mixed wine fermentation. Microb Cell Factories 11:1&#x2013;11 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciani M, Morales P, Comitini F, Tronchoni J, Canonico L, Curiel JA et al., Non&#x2010;conventional yeast species for lowering ethanol content of wines. Front Microbiol 7:642 (2016). https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2016.00642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canonico L, Comitini F, Oro L and Ciani M, Sequential fermentation with selected immobilized non&#x2010;Saccharomyces yeast for reduction of ethanol content in wine. Front Microbiol 7:278 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;cker J, Strub S, Ebert K and Grossmann M, Usage of different aerobic non&#x2010;Saccharomyces yeasts and experimental conditions as a tool for reducing the potential ethanol content in wines. Eur Food Res Technol 242:2051&#x2013;2070 (2016). https://doi.org/10.1007/s00217-016-2703-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehlomakulu N, Hoff J, Erten H, Beukes L and Jolly N, Screening non&#x2010;Saccharomyces yeasts as low ethanol producing starter cultures. S Afr J Enol Vitic 42:56&#x2013;66 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valera MJ, Olivera V, Boido E, Dellacassa E and Carrau F, Wine aroma characterization of the two main fermentation yeast species of the apiculate genus Hanseniaspora. Ferment 7:162 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortiz&#x2010;Barrera E, Miranda&#x2010;Castilleja DE, Arvizu&#x2010;Medrano SM, Pacheco&#x2010;Aguilar JR, Aldrete&#x2010;Tapia JA, Hern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Iturriaga M et al., Enological potential of native non&#x2010;saccharomyces yeasts from vineyards established in Queretaro, Mexico. Rev Chapingo Ser Hortic 21:169&#x2013;183 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andorr&#xe0; I, Berradre M, Mas A, Esteve&#x2010;Zarzoso B and Guillam&#xf3;n JM, Effect of mixed culture fermentations on yeast populations and aroma profile. LWT Food Sci Technol 49:8&#x2013;13 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albergaria H, Torr&#xe3;o AR, Hogg T and G&#xed;rio FM, Physiological behaviour of Hanseniaspora guilliermondii in aerobic glucose&#x2010;limited continuous cultures. FEMS Yeast Res 3:211&#x2013;216 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arneborg N, Siegumfeldt H, Andersen GH, Nissen P, Daria VR, Rodrigo PJ et al., Interactive optical trapping shows that confinement is a determinant of growth in a mixed yeast culture. FEMS Microbiol Lett 245:155&#x2013;159 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen P and Arneborg N, Characterization of early deaths of non&#x2010;saccharomyces yeasts in mixed cultures with Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Arch Microbiol 180:257&#x2013;263 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwoudt H, Prior BA, Pretorius IS and Bauer F, Glycerol in South African Table Wines: An Assessment of its Relationship to Wine Quality (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivit NN, Longo R and Kemp B, The effect of non&#x2010;saccharomyces and saccharomyces non&#x2010;cerevisiae yeasts on ethanol and glycerol levels in wine. Ferment 6:77 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tristezza M, Tufariello M, Capozzi V, Spano G, Mita G and Grieco F, The oenological potential of Hanseniaspora uvarum in simultaneous and sequential co&#x2010;fermentation with Saccharomyces cerevisiae for industrial wine production. Front Microbiol 7:670 (2016). https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2016.00670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg A and Adler L, Physiology of osmotolerance in fungi. Adv Microb Physiol 33:145&#x2013;212 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior B, Toh T, Jolly N, Baccari C and Mortimer R, Impact of yeast breeding for elevated glycerol production on fermentative activity and metabolite formation in chardonnay wine. S Afr J Enol Vitic 21:92&#x2013;99 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remize F, Roustan J, Sablayrolles J&#x2010;M, Barre P and Dequin S, Glycerol overproduction by engineered Saccharomyces cerevisiae wine yeast strains leads to substantial changes in by&#x2010;product formation and to a stimulation of fermentation rate in stationary phase. Appl Environ Microbiol 65:143&#x2013;149 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes MDB, Rehman A, Gockowiak H, Heinrich AJ, Langride P and Henschke PA, Fermentation properties of a wine yeast over&#x2010;expressing the Saccharomyces cerevisiae glycerol 3&#x2010;phosphate dehydrogenase gene (GPD2). Aust J Grape Wine Res 6:208&#x2013;215 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swiegers JH and Pretorius IS, Yeast modulation of wine flavor. Adv Appl Microbiol 57:131&#x2013;175 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Plessis M, Franken J and Bauer FF, Carnitine requires choline to exert physiological effects in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Front Microbiol 9:1362 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamero A, Ferreira V, Pretorius IS and Querol A, Wine, beer and cider: Unravelling the aroma profile. In Molecular Mechanisms in Yeast Carbon Metabolism. Springer, Heidelberg, pp. 261&#x2013;297 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balmaseda A, Bordons A, Reguant C and Bautista&#x2010;Gallego J, Non&#x2010;saccharomyces in wine: effect upon Oenococcus oeni and malolactic fermentation. Front Microbiol 9:534 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plav&#x161;a T, Jagati&#x107; Korenika A&#x2010;M, Luki&#x107; I, Bubola M and Jeromel A, Influence of different malolactic fermentation techniques on changes in chemical properties and volatile compounds of cv. Teran red wine (Vitis vinifera L). J Cent Eur Agric 22:582&#x2013;595 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pino JA and Queris O, Analysis of volatile compounds of pineapple wine using solid&#x2010;phase microextraction techniques. Food Chem 122:1241&#x2013;1246 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan Y and Siebert KJ, Quantitative structure&#x2212; activity relationship modeling of alcohol, ester, aldehyde, and ketone flavor thresholds in beer from molecular features. J Agric Food Chem 52:3057&#x2013;3064 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang X, Yuan G, Ren J, Wang L, Wang M, Li Y, Zhang B and Zhu B, Aromatic compounds and organoleptic features of fermented wolfberry wine: Effects of maceration time. Int J Food Prop 20:2234&#x2013;2248 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Plessis H, Du Toit M, Nieuwoudt H, Van der Rijst M, Hoff J and Jolly N, Modulation of wine flavor using Hanseniaspora uvarum in combination with different Saccharomyces cerevisiae, lactic acid bacteria strains and malolactic fermentation strategies. Ferment 5:64 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimopoulou M, Troianou V, Paramithiotis S, Proksenia N and Kotseridis Y, Evaluation of malolactic starters in white and ros&#xe9; winemaking of moschofilero wines. Appl Sci 12:5722 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello PJ, D&#xe9;l&#xe9;rus&#x2010;Bou M, Descenzo R, Hall N, Krieger S, Lonvaud&#x2010;Funel A et al., Malolactic fermentation&#x2010;importance of wine lactic acid bacteria in winemaking. Lallemand Incorporated, Canada (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YQ, Hu K, Xu YH, Mei WC and Tao YS, Biomass suppression of Hanseniaspora uvarum by killer Saccharomyces cerevisiae highly increased fruity esters in mixed culture fermentation. LWT Food Sci Technol 132:109839 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spano G and Torriani S, Microbiota of grapes: positive and negative role on wine quality. Front Microbiol 7:2036 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz V, Beccaria B and Abreo E, Simultaneous and successive inoculations of yeasts and lactic acid bacteria on the fermentation of an unsulfited Tannat grape must. Braz J Microbiol 45:59&#x2013;66 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehme N, Mathieu F and Taillandier P, Impact of the co&#x2010;culture of Saccharomyces cerevisiae&#x2013;Oenococcus oeni on malolactic fermentation and partial characterization of a yeast&#x2010;derived inhibitory peptidic fraction. Food Microbiol 27:150&#x2013;157 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrando N, Araque I, Ortis A, Thornes G, Bautista&#x2010;Gallego J, Bordons A and Reguant C, Evaluating the effect of using non&#x2010;Saccharomyces on Oenococcus oeni and wine malolactic fermentation. Int Food Res 138:109779 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonvaud&#x2010;Funel A, Lactic acid bacteria in the quality improvement and depreciation of wine, in Lactic Acid Bacteria: Genetics, Metabolism and Applications: Proceedings of the Sixth Symposium on Lactic Acid Bacteria: Genetics, Metabolism and Applications. Springer, Netherlands, pp. 317&#x2013;331 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerm E, Engelbrecht L and Du Toit M, Malolactic Fermentation: The ABC's of MLF (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jitjaroen W, Bouphun T and Panjai L, The potential of malolactic fermentation on organic acids degradation in Mao (Antidesma Thwaitesanum M&#xfc;ell.) wine production. IJBB 3:368&#x2013;371 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulton RB, Singleton VL, Bisson LF and Kunkee RE, Principles and Practices of Winemaking. Springer Science &amp; Business Media, Germany (2013).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>