<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110408</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Flour and parenchyma cells from sweet potato and potato: a comparative study of their physicochemical properties and digestibility.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1327</StartPage><EndPage>1337</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1327-1337</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01777-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In tuber crops, starch granules are enveloped in parenchyma cells (PCs) which are bound together by pectin-rich middle lamella. Flour and intact PCs were isolated from sweet potato (Shinyulmi cultivar) and potato (Dejima cultivar). Starch granules and PCs of potato were larger than those of sweet potato. PCs from both species had lower contents of crude ash, crude protein, and crude lipid compared to their flour counterparts. As temperatures rose, the solubility patterns varied between flour and PC of sweet potato, while remaining consistent for potato. Potato PC had higher gelatinization temperatures compared to its flour counterpart, while sweet potato PC had lower temperatures than its flour, possibly due to the considerable loss of non-starch polysaccharide during its PC preparation. Compared to cooking, baked PCs showed a more evident inhibition on digestion. This study suggests that such species differences need to be considered when utilizing PCs in food processing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2024. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Jong Hyun</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Institute of Life Science and Resources, Kyung Hee University, Youngin, 17104 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01zqcg218</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.289247.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2171 7818</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bae</LastName><ForeName>Ji-Eun</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Nutrition, College of Fisheries Science, Pukyong National University, Busan, 48513 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0433kqc49</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412576.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0719 8994</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baik</LastName><ForeName>Moo-Yeol</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Institute of Life Science and Resources, Kyung Hee University, Youngin, 17104 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01zqcg218</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.289247.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2171 7818</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Seon Hye</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Graduate school, Kyonggi University, Suwon, 16227 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/032xf8h46</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411203.5</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0691 2332</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ocean and Fisheries Development International Cooperation Institute, Pukyong National University, Busan, 48513 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0433kqc49</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412576.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0719 8994</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyun-Seok</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Institute of Life Science and Resources, Kyung Hee University, Youngin, 17104 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/01zqcg218</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.289247.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2171 7818</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flour</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In vitro digestion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parenchyma cell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physicochemical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potato</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sweet potato</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors claim no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01777-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AACC. Approved method of the AACC (In Methods). American Association of Cereal Chemists., (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agnes, A., Felix, E., &amp; Ugochukwu, N. Morphology, rheology and functional properties of starch from cassava, sweet potato and cocoyam. Asian Journal of Biology, 3: 1-13 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilera, J. M., Cadoche, L., L&#xf3;pez, C., &amp; Gutierrez, G. Microstructural changes of potato cells and starch granules heated in oil. Food Research International, 34: 939-947 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C Allen, J., D Corbitt, A., P Maloney, K., S Butt, M., &amp; Truong, V.-D. Glycemic index of sweet potato as affected by cooking methods. The Open Nutrition Journal, 6: (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anantachote. A. Chemical-assisted separation and characterization of parenchyma cells from potatoes (Solanum tuberosum). University of Idaho (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avula, R. Y. (2005). Rheological and functional properties of potato and sweet potato flour and evaluation of its application in some selected food products. University Of Mysore.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avula, R. Y., &amp; Singh, R. K. Functional properties of potato flour and its role in product development&#x2013;A review. Food, 3: 105-112 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae, J.-E., Hong, J. S., Baik, M.-Y., Choi, H.-D., Choi, H.-W., &amp; Kim, H.-S. Impact of starch granule-associated surface and channel proteins on physicochemical properties of corn and rice starches. Carbohydrate polymers, 250: 116908 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33049831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzera, A., Gikundi, E., Orina, I., &amp; Sila, D. Effect of Pretreatments and Drying Methods on Physical and Microstructural Properties of Potato Flour. Foods, 11: (2022). doi: 10.3390/foods11040507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8871150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35205983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, L., Huang, Q., Xiang, W., Fu, X., Zhang, B., &amp; Wu, J.-Y. Chemical cross-linking reduces in vitro starch digestibility of cooked potato parenchyma cells. Food Hydrocolloids, 124: 107297 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do, D. T., Singh, J., Oey, I., &amp; Singh, H. Isolated potato parenchyma cells: Physico-chemical characteristics and gastro-small intestinal digestion in vitro. Food Hydrocolloids, 108: 105972 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuis, J. H., &amp; Liu, Q. Potato starch: A review of physicochemical, functional and nutritional properties. American Journal of Potato Research, 96: 127-138 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englyst, H. N., Kingman, S., &amp; Cummings, J. Classification and measurement of nutritionally important starch fractions. European journal of clinical nutrition, 46: S33-50 (1992).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1330528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuentes-Zaragoza, E., S&#xe1;nchez-Zapata, E., Sendra, E., Sayas, E., Navarro, C., Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xf3;pez, J., &amp; P&#xe9;rez-Alvarez, J. A. Resistant starch as prebiotic: A review. Starch-St&#xe4;rke, 63: 406-415 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomand, S., Lamberts, L., Derde, L., Goesaert, H., Vandeputte, G., Goderis, B.,. . Delcour, J. Structural properties and gelatinisation characteristics of potato and cassava starches and mutants thereof. Food hydrocolloids, 24: 307-317 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, H., Zhang, Y., Hong, Y., Bi, Y., Gu, Z., Cheng, L.,. . Li, C. Digestibility and changes to structural characteristics of green banana starch during in vitro digestion. Food Hydrocolloids, 49: 192-199 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karim, A. A., Toon, L. C., Lee, V. P., Ong, W. Y., Fazilah, A., &amp; Noda, T. Effects of phosphorus contents on the gelatinization and retrogradation of potato starch. J Food Sci, 72: C132-138 (2007). doi: 10.1111/j.1750-3841.2006.00251.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17995828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H.-S., &amp; Huber, K. C. Physicochemical properties and amylopectin fine structures of A-and B-type granules of waxy and normal soft wheat starch. Journal of Cereal Science, 51: 256-264 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, E.-J., &amp; Kim, H.-S. Physicochemical properties of dehydrated potato parenchyma cells with ungelatinized and gelatinized starches. Carbohydrate polymers, 117: 845-852 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25498708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larder, C. E., Abergel, M., Kubow, S., &amp; Donnelly, D. J. Freeze-drying affects the starch digestibility of cooked potato tubers. Food Res Int, 103: 208-214 (2018). doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2017.10.034</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29389607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H., &amp; Kim, H.-S. Isolation and physicochemical property of individual parenchyma cells from mealy sweet potato. Food Science and Biotechnology, 29: 521-529 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7142175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32296563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, N., Seo, J.-M., Kim, H.-S., Seo, D.-H., Kim, J., Choi, H., &amp; Lee, B.-H. Citric-acid treatment during rice processing increases the level of slowly digestible starch with a potential to regulate the post-prandial blood glucose level. Journal of Cereal Science, 89: 102821 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, E., Cao, P., Cao, W., &amp; Li, C. Relations between starch fine molecular structures with gelatinization property under different moisture content. Carbohydrate Polymers, 278: 118955 (2022a).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34973771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Zhao, L., Lin, L., Li, E., Cao, Q., &amp; Wei, C. Relationships between X-ray diffraction peaks, molecular components, and heat properties of C-type starches from different sweet potato varieties. Molecules, 27: 3385 (2022b).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9182557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35684323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, P. Y., &amp; Czuchajowska, Z. Role of phosphorus in viscosity, gelatinization, and retrogradation of starch. Cereal Chemistry, 75: 705-709 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noda, T., Takahata, Y., Nagata, T., &amp; Monma, M. Digestibility of sweet potato raw starches by glucoamylase. Starch-St&#xe4;rke, 44: 32-35 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurdjanah, S. (2008). Extraction and characterisation of pectin from Australian and Indonesian sweet potato. UNSW Sydney.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwokocha, L. M., Aviara, N. A., Senan, C., &amp; Williams, P. A. A comparative study of properties of starches from Irish potato (Solanum tuberosum) and sweet potato (Ipomea batatas) grown in Nigeria. Starch-St&#xe4;rke, 66: 714-723 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osundahunsi, O. F., Fagbemi, T. N., Kesselman, E., &amp; Shimoni, E. Comparison of the physicochemical properties and pasting characteristics of flour and starch from red and white sweet potato cultivars. J Agric Food Chem, 51: 2232-2236 (2003). doi: 10.1021/jf0260139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralet, M.-C., Buffetto, F., Capron, I., &amp; Guillon, F. (2016). Cell wall polysaccharides of potato Advances in potato chemistry and technology (pp. 33-56): Elsevier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy, N. N., &amp; Sistrunk, W. Effect of cultivar, size, storage, and cooking method on carbohydrates and some nutrients of sweet potatoes. Journal of Food Science, 45: 682-684 (1980).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reyniers, S., De Brier, N., Matthijs, S., Brijs, K., &amp; Delcour, J. A. Impact of physical and enzymatic cell wall opening on the release of pre-gelatinized starch and viscosity forming potential of potato flakes. Carbohydr Polym, 194: 401-410 (2018). doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2018.04.057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29801855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz, S., Walter Jr, W., Carroll, D., &amp; Giesbrecht, F. Chemical, physical, and sensory properties of a sweet potato french-fry type product during frozen storage. Journal of Food Science, 52: 617-619 (1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin, E.-H., Baik, M.-Y., &amp; Kim, H.-S. Comparison of physicochemical properties of starches and parenchyma cells isolated from potatoes cultivated in Korea. Food Science and Biotechnology, 24: 955-963 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;&#xf6;, M., Eliasson, A.-C., &amp; Autio, K. Comparison of different microscopic methods for the study of starch and other components within potato cells. Foods, 3: 39-44 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taguchi, T., Onishi, M., Katsuno, N., Miwa, N., Oomoto, C., Sato, M.,. . Nishizu, T. Evaluation of starch retrogradation by X-ray diffraction using a water-addition method. Lwt, 173: 114341 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallet, C., Chabbert, B., Czaninski, Y., &amp; Monties, B. Histochemistry of lignin deposition during sclerenchyma differentiation in alfalfa stems. Annals of Botany625&#x2013;632 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, A. R., Guha, M., Tharanathan, R., &amp; Ramteke, R. Influence of drying conditions on functional properties of potato flour. European Food Research and Technology, 223: 553-560 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye, F., Li, J., &amp; Zhao, G. Physicochemical properties of different-sized fractions of sweet potato starch and their contributions to the quality of sweet potato starch. Food Hydrocolloids, 108: 106023 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaidul, I., Norulaini, N. N., Omar, A. M., Yamauchi, H., &amp; Noda, T. RVA analysis of mixtures of wheat flour and potato, sweet potato, yam, and cassava starches. Carbohydrate polymers, 69: 784-791 (2007).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>