<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40110397</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fermented soybean powder containing S-equol alleviates the postmenopausal signs of ovariectomized rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1495</StartPage><EndPage>1505</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1495-1505</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01768-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Menopausal symptoms, including hot flashes, metabolic changes, and osteoporosis, significantly impact postmenopausal women. Given concerns about hormone replacement therapy, S-equol, a metabolite of the soybean isoflavone daidzein, has emerged as a potential alternative. This study explored the efficacy of S-equol-containing-supplement (SE5-OH), a fermented soy germ containing S-equol, on menopausal symptoms and osteoporosis in 6-month-old and 8-week-old ovariectomized (OVX) rat models. SE5-OH did not affect uterine weight or endometrial thickness but significantly reduced body weight in 8-week-old OVX rats (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). SE5-OH also decreased estrogen receptor upregulation in the liver and hypothalamus. In the hypothalamus, SE5-OH downregulated calcitonin gene-related peptide levels, which are linked to hot flashes and osteoporosis (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Additionally, SE5-OH stabilized the bone-formation marker RANKL/OPG, tended to increase estrogen receptor levels in tibial bone tissue and increased serum bone-turnover biomarkers. In conclusion, SE5-OH may alleviate postmenopausal symptoms, including hot flashes, lipid metabolism changes, and osteoporosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s10068-024-01768-w.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2024. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Byung Hee</ForeName><Initials>BH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nano Bio Engineering, Seoul National University of Science and Technology, 232, Gongneung-Ro, Nowon-Gu, Seoul, 01811 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00chfja07</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412485.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9760 4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Kwanyong</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Seoul National University of Science and Technology, 232, Gongneung-Ro, Nowon-Gu, Seoul, 01811 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00chfja07</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412485.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9760 4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Soo-Yeon</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Seoul National University of Science and Technology, 232, Gongneung-Ro, Nowon-Gu, Seoul, 01811 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00chfja07</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412485.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9760 4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Ji Yeon</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4316-2726</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Biotechnology, Seoul National University of Science and Technology, 232, Gongneung-Ro, Nowon-Gu, Seoul, 01811 Republic of Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/00chfja07</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412485.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9760 4919</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Estrogen receptor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hot flash</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Menopause</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoporosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">S-equol</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40110397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01768-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aso T, Uchiyama S, Matsumura Y, Taguchi M, Nozaki M, Takamatsu K, Ishizuka B, Kubota T, Mizunuma H, Ohta H. A natural S-equol supplement alleviates hot flushes and other menopausal symptoms in equol nonproducing postmenopausal Japanese women. Journal of women's health 21: 92-100 (2012)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21992596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bord S, Ireland D, Beavan S, Compston J. The effects of estrogen on osteoprotegerin, RANKL, and estrogen receptor expression in human osteoblasts. Bone 32: 136-141 (2003)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12633785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukijrungroat N, Khamphaya T, Weerachayaphorn J, Songserm T, Saengsirisuwan V. Hepatic FGF21 mediates sex differences in high-fat high-fructose diet-induced fatty liver. American Journal of Physiology-Endocrinology and Metabolism 313: E203-E212 (2017)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28559436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark RG, Tarttelin MF. Some effects of ovariectomy and estrogen replacement on body composition in the rat. Physiology &amp; Behavior 28: 963-969 (1982)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7111460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman R, Brown J, Terpos E, Lipton A, Smith MR, Cook R, Major P. Bone markers and their prognostic value in metastatic bone disease: clinical evidence and future directions. Cancer treatment reviews 34: 629-639 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diel P. Tissue-specific estrogenic response and molecular mechanisms. Toxicology letters 127: 217-224 (2002)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12052661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost HM, Jee WS. On the rat model of human osteopenias and osteoporoses. Bone and mineral 18: 227-236 (1992)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1392696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon A, Aguilar R, Garrido-Gracia JC, Guil-Luna S, Sanchez-Cespedes R, Millan Y, Martin de las Mulas J, Sanchez-Criado JE. Activation of estrogen receptor-&#x3b1; induces gonadotroph progesterone receptor expression and action differently in young and middle-aged ovariectomized rats. Human Reproduction 24: 2618-2628 (2009)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grigoryan AV, Dimitrova AA, Kostov KG, Russeva AL, Atanasova MA, Blagev AB, Betova TM, Trifonov RG. Changes of serum concentrations of alkaline phosphatase and metalloproteinase-9 in an ovariectomized wistar rat model of osteoporosis. Journal of Biomedical and Clinical Research 10: 32-36 (2017)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao L, Wang Y, Duan Y, Bu S. Effects of treadmill exercise training on liver fat accumulation and estrogen receptor alpha expression in intact and ovariectomized rats with or without estrogen replacement treatment. European Journal of Applied Physiology 109: 879-886 (2010)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20232078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishiwata N, Melby MK, Mizuno S, Watanabe S. New equol supplement for relieving menopausal symptoms: randomized, placebo-controlled trial of Japanese women. Menopause 16: 141-8 (2009)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson RL, Greiwe JS, Schwen RJ. Emerging evidence of the health benefits of S-equol, an estrogen receptor &#x3b2; agonist. Nutrition reviews 69: 432-448 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21790611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jilka RL, Hangoc G, Girasole G, Passeri G, Williams DC, Abrams JS, Boyce B, Broxmeyer H, Manolagas SC. Increased osteoclast development after estrogen loss: mediation by interleukin-6. Science 257: 88-91 (1992)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1621100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid AB, Krum SA. Estrogen receptors alpha and beta in bone. Bone 87: 130-135 (2016)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5336249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27072516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishida T, Mizushige T, Ohtsu Y, Ishikawa S, Nagamoto M, Izumi T, Obata A, Ebihara K. Dietary soy isoflavone-aglycone lowers food intake in female rats with and without ovariectomy. Obesity (Silver Spring) 16: 290-7 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Ishimi Y, Takebayashi J, Tousen Y. Assessment of safety and efficacy of pine bark extract in normal and ovariectomized mice. Journal of food science 85: 1956-1962 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32406939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Liang B, Shi X, Wang H. Opg/Rankl mRNA dynamic expression in the bone tissue of ovariectomized rats with osteoporosis. Genet Mol Res 14: 9215-24 (2015)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26345854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Shi H. Regulation of estrogen receptor &#x3b1; expression in the hypothalamus by sex steroids: implication in the regulation of energy homeostasis. International journal of endocrinology 2015: 949085 (2015)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4600542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26491443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matulka RA, Matsuura I, Uesugi T, Ueno T, Burdock G. Developmental and reproductive effects of SE5&#x2010;OH: an equol&#x2010;rich soy&#x2010;based ingredient. Journal of Toxicology 2009: 307618 (2009)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20107584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morito K, Hirose T, Kinjo J, HIRAKAWA T, OKAWA M, NOHARA T, OGAWA S, INOUE S, MURAMATSU M, MASAMUNE Y. Interaction of phytoestrogens with estrogen receptors &#x3b1; and &#x3b2;. Biological and Pharmaceutical Bulletin 24: 351-356 (2001)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishide Y, Tadaishi M, Kobori M, Tousen Y, Kato M, Inada M, Miyaura C, Ishimi Y. Possible role of S-equol on bone loss via amelioration of inflammatory indices in ovariectomized mice. J Clin Biochem Nutr 53: 41-8 (2013)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3705151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23874069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noguchi M, Ikarashi Y, Yuzurihara M, Mizoguchi K, Kurauchi K, Chen J, Ishige A. Up-regulation of calcitonin gene-related peptide receptors underlying elevation of skin temperature in ovariectomized rats. Journal of endocrinology 175: 177-184 (2002)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rance NE. Menopause and the human hypothalamus: evidence for the role of kisspeptin/neurokinin B neurons in the regulation of estrogen negative feedback. Peptides 30: 111-122 (2009)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2632595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18614256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro N. Symptoms of menopause: hot flushes. Clinical obstetrics and gynecology 51: 539-548 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18677148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt E, Dekant W, Stopper H. Assaying the estrogenicity of phytoestrogens in cells of different estrogen sensitive tissues. Toxicology in vitro 15: 433-439 (2001)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11566575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setchell KD, Clerici C, Lephart ED, Cole SJ, Heenan C, Castellani D, Wolfe BE, Nechemias-Zimmer L, Brown NM, Lund TD. S-Equol, a potent ligand for estrogen receptor &#x3b2;, is the exclusive enantiomeric form of the soy isoflavone metabolite produced by human intestinal bacterial flora1&#x2013;4. The American journal of clinical nutrition 81: 1072-1079 (2005)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka T, Iwamoto K, Wada M, Yano E, Suzuki T, Kawaguchi N, Shirasaka N, Moriyama T, Homma Y. Dietary syringic acid reduces fat mass in an ovariectomy-induced mouse model of obesity. Menopause 28: 1340-1350 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34610616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tantikanlayaporn D, Wichit P, Weerachayaphorn J, Chairoungdua A, Chuncharunee A, Suksamrarn A, Piyachaturawat P. Bone sparing effect of a novel phytoestrogen diarylheptanoid from Curcuma comosa Roxb. in ovariectomized rats. PloS one 8: e78739 (2013)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3823985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24244350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tousen Y, Ezaki J, Fujii Y, Ueno T, Nishimuta M, Ishimi Y. Natural S-equol decreases bone resorption in postmenopausal, non-equol-producing Japanese women: a pilot randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Menopause 18: 563-74 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21252728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinogradova Y, Coupland C, Hippisley-Cox J. Use of hormone replacement therapy and risk of breast cancer: nested case-control studies using the QResearch and CPRD databases. Bmj 371 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33115755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss G, Skurnick JH, Goldsmith LT, Santoro NF, Park SJ. Menopause and hypothalamic-pituitary sensitivity to estrogen. Jama 292: 2991-2996 (2004)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15613667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wronski TJ, Schenck PA, Cintr&#xf3;n M, Walsh CC. Effect of body weight on osteopenia in ovariectomized rats. Calcif Tissue Int 40: 155-9 (1987)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3105846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yee S, Burdock GA, Kurata Y, Enomoto Y, Narumi K, Hamada S, Itoh T, Shimomura Y, Ueno T. Acute and subchronic toxicity and genotoxicity of SE5-OH, an equol-rich product produced by Lactococcus garvieae. Food and Chemical Toxicology 46: 2713-2720 (2008)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18554770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoneda T, Ueno T, Uchiyama S. S-equol and the fermented soy product SE5-OH containing S-equol similarly decrease ovariectomy-induced increase in rat tail skin temperature in an animal model of hot flushes. Menopause 18: 814-820 (2011)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21451423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R-h, Zhang X-b, Lu Y-b, Hu Y-c, Chen X-y, Yu D-c, Shi J-t, Yuan W-h, Wang J, Zhou H-y. Calcitonin gene-related peptide and brain-derived serotonin are related to bone loss in ovariectomized rats. Brain Research Bulletin 176: 85-92 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>